<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>The Tech Genie</title>
    <link href="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie" />
    <updated>2023-11-10T19:53:47+09:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Will Ellington</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Real world cases where a VPN is actually useful</title>
        <author>
            <name>Will Ellington</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/real-world-cases-where-a-vpn-is-actually-useful/"/>
        <id>https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/real-world-cases-where-a-vpn-is-actually-useful/</id>
        <media:content url="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/media/posts/1/privecstasy-CXlqHmQy3MY-unsplash-2.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-11-10T19:53:47+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/media/posts/1/privecstasy-CXlqHmQy3MY-unsplash-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    VPNs are not a panacea for web security, but the internet world is defintiely divided between those who do and don't have a VPN. Below are some real world use cases where a VPN has helped prevent a serious problem. Protecting against cybercrime: A user&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://will-ellington.github.io/tech-genie/media/posts/1/privecstasy-CXlqHmQy3MY-unsplash-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>VPNs are not a panacea for web security, but the internet world is defintiely divided between those who do and don't have a VPN. Below are some real world use cases where a VPN has helped prevent a serious problem.</p>
<ol class="list-outside list-decimal marker:font-mono marker:text-sm pl-11">
<li><span class=""><strong>Protecting against cybercrime</strong>: A user was the victim of a cybercrime and had their personal information stolen. They started using a VPN to encrypt their internet traffic and protect their data from future attacks. The VPN also helped them access their bank account and other sensitive information securely.<br><br></span></li>
<li><span class=""><strong>Working remotely</strong>: A user was working remotely and needed to access their company's network and files. By using a VPN, they were able to securely connect to their company's network and access the files they needed without compromising the security of the company's data. <br><br></span></li>
<li><span class=""><strong>Avoiding online price discrimination</strong>: A user noticed that they were being charged more for flights and hotel bookings when they searched from their home country. By using a VPN to connect to a server in a different country, they were able to avoid online price discrimination and save money on their bookings.<br><br></span></li>
<li><span class=""><span class=""><strong>Accessing online gaming servers</strong></span><span class="">: A user was unable to connect to online gaming servers due to geographical restrictions. By using a VPN to connect to a server in a different location, they were able to bypass the restrictions and connect to the gaming servers they needed.<br><br></span></span></li>
<li><span class=""><span class=""><strong>Protecting against workplace surveillance</strong></span><span class="">: A user was concerned that their employer was monitoring their internet activity while working remotely. By using a VPN, they were able to encrypt their internet traffic and prevent their employer from tracking their online activity.<br><br></span></span></li>
<li><span class=""><span class=""><strong>Protecting against cyberstalking</strong></span><span class="">: A user was being cyberstalked and wanted to protect their online activity from the stalker. By using a VPN, they were able to mask their IP address and prevent the stalker from tracking their online activity.</span></span></li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
